Emergency!
紧急呼叫
Patrol car 503 calling Metropolitan Police Department.
警视503呼叫警视厅
Patrol car 503, over.
警视503请回答
We found the car driven by the armed robbers, who are on wanted list!
现在发现正在通缉的持枪抢劫车辆
They're fleeing from Satobari Road to Gyoki Road.
正从外堀路逃向御幸路
Roger that.
警视厅收到
Please state both the license plate number and the appearance of the suspects' vehicle,
请告诉我们可疑车辆的车牌 车型
and the suspects' physical descriptions, over.
和嫌疑犯的外貌特征　请说
Roger that.
警视503收到
The suspects' vehicle is a black SUV.
可疑车辆是黑色箱型车
Its plate number is Shinjuku 500 SA 32-55.
新宿500 Sa 32-55
The suspects' physical descriptions are...
犯人的外观特征是…
Rupan and Fujiko...
鲁邦和…不二子
Patrol car 503, please stop kidding.
警视503 请不要胡说
I'm not kidding...
我没有胡说！
Patrol car 503 calling Metropolitan Police Department!
警视503呼叫警视厅
Rupan is turning left from Gyoki Road onto Chuo Road!
鲁邦从御幸路左转到中央路了
Patrol car 503, please cut the crap, over.
警视503 你有完没完啊 请说
I told you I'm not kidding!
我都说我没有胡说了
Hey, Officer Sato...
喂 佐…佐藤警官
Please drive a little more carefully.
请保持安全驾驶
Shouldn't you still be contacting headquarters?
你难道不用联络本部了吗？
Yes...
好…
Patrol car 503 calling Metropolitan Police Department!
警视503呼叫警视厅
Suspects are turning right onto Harumi Road.
犯人右转进入了晴海路
How dare he wear Rupan mask for a robbery!
竟然敢戴鲁邦的面具抢劫
Unforgivable!
不能原谅！
Welcome. Good evening.
欢迎光临 晚安
That's 1,237 yen in total.
一共是1237元
Pull your car over right now!
前面那辆车马上停车！
There must be some case, huh?
发生什么案件了吧？
That's cool!
好酷喔
Pull your car over right now!
前面那辆车马上停车！
I'll repeat once more!
我再重复一次
You have nowhere to run!
你们已经无处可逃了
Pull your car over there!
把车给我停到路边去
How dare he be so cocky?
竟敢这么嚣张
In that case, I'll pay you back with an eye for an eye!
那我就以眼还眼 以牙还牙
Officer Sato!
佐藤警官
They're getting away.
这样会被他们逃走的
Hold on tight.
好好抓紧了
Officer Sato, what are you doing?
佐藤警官 你想干什么？
You'll bite your tongue if you keep talking.
说话小心咬到舌头
Officer Sato?
佐…佐藤警官？
Be quiet!
安静
Wait... Wait a minute, Officer Sato.
等…等一下 佐藤警官
Takagi, contact headquarters!
高木 快联络本部
Got it!
知道了
Geez...
真是的…
Officer Sato!
佐藤警官
Backup and ambulances are on their way.
支援的警车和救护车马上就到
He's got it coming.
真是自作自受
He shouldn't have worn my first love's mask.
谁叫他戴着我初恋情人的面具
First...first love?
初…初恋情人啊？
Go take a look at Fujiko.
你去看看不二子
Okay.
好的
Hang in there!
振作一点！
The ambulance will be here soon.
救护车马上就来了
Officer Sato.
佐藤警官
Fujiko's just passed out.
不二子也只是昏了过去
I think she's only slightly injured.
好像只受了轻伤
Really?
是吗？
But why would they rob in such funny masks?
但是为什么他们要戴这种搞笑的面具抢劫？
Koumi... Koumi Island...
神…神海岛…
Koumi Island?
神海岛？
So you were trying to rob the money so that you could take a vacation on that island?
想用抢来的钱去那座岛上玩吗？
No...no.
不…不是
No?
不是…？
Is there anything on that island?
那座岛上有什么吗？
Jolly...
JOLLY…
Jolly Roger...
JOLLY ROGER
Jolly Roger?
JOLLY ROGER？
Have you ever heard of it?
你有听过吗？
Well...
这个嘛…
Mom, hurry up!
妈妈 快点快点
Let's go over there.
去那边吧
Wait for me!
等等我啊
Do you know how to use this?
这个要怎么用呢？
Let me show you.
我做给你看
Sensei, what kind of fish are here?
老师 这里有什么样的鱼呢？
Good morning.
早安
May I have the name you made reservations under?
您预约的姓名是…
Kogoro Mouri, the famous detective.
毛利小五郎 是个名侦探
2 adults, 2 students,
2个大人 2个学生
and 5 children.
还有5个小孩
Please wait a moment.
请稍等一下
The Nichiuri Paper publishes a puzzle to solve each week, right?
《日卖报纸》不是每周都会刊登一次拼图猜谜吗？
The ones which are super hard.
就是超级难的那个
The prize money keeps accumulating if no one answers correctly.
没有人答对的话奖金就会一直累积
And then it even reached 300,000 yen!
到后来居然累积到了30万
Do you know who finally answered correctly and won 300,000 yen?
你知道最后谁答对了 并且获得了30万呢？
Well...
这个嘛…
Oh, could it be...
难道是…
Bingo!
答对了！
I'm a famous detective, after all.
再怎么说我也是个名侦探
That kind of puzzle is a piece of cake for me.
那种拼图猜谜对于我来说简直易如反掌
But the one who solved it is me...
不过 解出来的人是我就是了…
With 300,000 yen, I can spend a leisurely vacation in Paris.
如果有30万的话就可以悠闲的在巴黎度假了
Because the streets of Paris are absolutely my style.
因为巴黎的街道跟我是最相配的了
But then I thought I shouldn't have all the fun myself.
但是我想了一下 一个人去享乐似乎不太好
Since we don't have many opportunities like this,
既然机会难得
I decided to bring them here and have fun together.
就让他们一起来开心一下
That's my idea.
我就是这么想的
I'm a nice guy, huh?
我人不错吧？
Yeah...
是…
So, what are our room numbers?
那么 我们房间是几号呢？
I'm really sorry.
实在对不起
It seems that we didn't receive your reservation.
我们似乎没有接到您的订房预约
Seriously?
真的假的？
Hey, hey...
喂…喂…
Wait...wait a minute.
等…等一下
I'm sure I made a reservation!
我明明有预约了啊
But I didn't find your name on the reservation list.
但是在预约的名单上找不到您的名字
Are we going to sleep on the street?
难道我们要露宿街头
This is a sub-tropical island.
这座岛位于亚热带
There might be poisonous bugs here.
可能会出现毒虫的
I wouldn't come here if I knew this earlier.
早知道就不来了
There must be a solution.
应该会有解决的办法的
It's not like we're in a foreign country where we speak a different language.
这里又不是语言不通的国外
Haibara-san looks like an adult.
灰原好像大人喔
At least we can be sure that she is not a child.
至少可以肯定她不是小孩
The front desk said they'll call the Tourism Division.
柜台说会打电话联络观光课
There's nothing to worry about, I guess.
应该是不用担心
I'm sorry.
不好意思
But when on the phone, that man promised me
对方明明是在电话中就说
the reservation was confirmed.
已经预订好了的
Well, you really made me confused.
您这么说我也很困扰
Hello, everyone. Sorry to keep you waiting.
大家好 让各位久等了
You must be Mr. Kogoro Mouri-san,
您就是毛利小五郎先生吧？
the famous detective...
那位名侦探…
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm Iwanaga from the Tourism Division.
我是观光课的岩永
The amount of tourists has suddenly increased this month.
这个月游客的数量突然增加很多
All the hotels are full.
每家旅馆都已经客满了
Actually, we're quite happy for this busyness.
虽然大家很忙 但都很高兴
But I've managed to make your reservations.
不过呢 我还是帮大家订到了旅馆
After all, you are the famous detective, Kogoro Mouri.
您毕竟是名侦探毛利小五郎嘛
Please come with me. I'll show you the way.
请跟过来吧 我来带路
I can't bear with that guy. What's wrong with him?
真受不了 那家伙怎么搞的啊
Who are those guys?
那些家伙是什么人啊？
They must be treasure hunters, I guess.
应该是宝藏猎人吧
Treasure hunters?
宝藏猎人？
Are they plumbers?
是修水管的人吗？
Flushing toilets or something like that?
元太把日语里的宝藏[トレージャ]听成了厕所冲水[トイレでジャする]的缩略 就是到别人家厕所冲水的啊
It's not like that, Genta-kun.
不是啦 元太
They are people who look for treasures all over the world.
是在全世界各地搜寻宝藏的人们
But how do you know that they are treasure hunters?
但是 你是怎么知道他们是宝藏猎人的呢？
Take a closer look at them.
你们仔细看看
Those guys are very tanned,
那些人虽然被晒得很黑
but only on their hands and heads, and not anywhere else, right?
但除了手掌和头部以外 其它地方都没有这么黑吧
This means they always wear diving suits.
这就表示他们是常穿着潜水衣的
And the color of their hair has faded because of the sea water.
而且头发的颜色也因海水而褪色
But if that's the case,
但是 如果是这样的话
maybe they are just people who like diving, right?
说不定他们只是喜欢潜水的人吧？
Indeed, you're right.
的确是这样没有错
But if you look at that poster,
不过要是看到那张海报
you'll know why I would think that way.
我会这么想也不奇怪吧？
(Koumi Island, How about coming along and looking for ancient treasures?)
神海岛 海底宫殿 沉睡之岛 你也一起来寻找古代宝藏吧
Ah... Treasure!
啊…宝藏！
That's right.
没错
They're probably dreaming...
他们大概在梦想着
Dreaming of getting the treasure sleeping at the bottom of the sea.
梦想得到沉睡在大海中的宝藏
(Detective Conan Jolly Roger in the Deep Azure)
名侦探柯南 深蓝的海盗旗
I am a high school detective, Shinichi Kudo.
我是高中生侦探工藤新一
What? I don't look like a high schooler?
啊 我看起来不像高中生？
She is my childhood friend and my classmate, Ran Mouri.
她是我的青梅竹马也是我的同班同学—毛利兰
When I went to the amusement park with Ran,
我和小兰一起去游乐园玩的时候
I witnessed a suspicious transaction made by a man in black.
无意间目击了一名黑衣男子正与人进行可疑交易
I was too preoccupied with watching at that time,
由于我太专注于他们交易的情况
and didn't notice another accomplice approaching from behind.
没有注意到他们另一名同伙就在我背后
He made me take the poison by force.
我被那个男人灌下毒药…
When I woke up, I found...
当我清醒时 却发现…
my body became smaller.
我的身体居然变小了！
If those guys knew that Shinichi Kudo was still alive,
若是那些人知道工藤新一还活着
not only would my life be in danger,
不但我的性命会再度受到威胁
but I would also get people around me involved.
更有可能让我周围的人受到池鱼之殃
At the suggestion of Professor Agasa, I concealed my true identity.
我听从阿笠博士的建议 打算就此隐瞒我的身份
When Ran asked me for my name,
当小兰问我姓名时
I took the name of Conan Edogawa.
我就编出了“江户川柯南”这个名字
Ran's father is a detective.
由于小兰的爸爸是个侦探
In order to collect information about those guys, I moved in with Ran.
为了收集那群人的相关情报 我便寄宿在小兰家中
This middle-aged man is Ran's father, Detective Kogoro Mouri.
这位大叔就是小兰的父亲 侦探毛利小五郎
He is known as the "Sleeping Kogoro".
人称“沉睡的小五郎”
As for the reason...
至于原因嘛…
That's what happened.
就是这么回事
She is Sonoko Suzuki.
她是铃木园子
She's Ran's classmate.
是小兰的同班同学
By the look of her, you would never know she comes from a wealthy family.
一点都不像一个千金大小姐
She is an easy-going girl.
是个很容易相处的人
This old man is Professor Agasa.
这个大叔是阿笠博士
Professor has invented a lot of interesting gadgets
博士为了身体变小的我
for me since my body became smaller.
发明了很多有趣的道具
She is Ai Haibara.
她是灰原哀
Her real name is Shiho Miyano.
本名叫宫野志保
She used to work with those guys in black.
她原来是那些黑衣人的同伙
But when she escaped from the organization,
但是在她逃出组织的时候
she took the same drug as the poison I took.
吃下了与我同样的毒药
Her body has become smaller as well.
所以身体也缩小了
Although I don't know the true identities of the men in black yet,
虽然现在还不知道那些黑衣人的真面目
I swear on my honor as a detective,
不过赌上侦探之名
I'll have it out with them one day.
我一定要和他们做个了结
Although my body is smaller, my mind is still flexible.
即使身形变小 头脑却一样清晰
The famous detective who can solve all kinds of cases.
没有迷宫的名侦探
Only one truth will prevail!
真相永远只有一个！
Speaking of which...
不过话说回来
Why would treasure hunters come here?
为什么会有宝藏猎人来这里？
Because someone found some treasure here two weeks ago.
因为差不多两个星期以前在这发现有宝藏
Treasure?
宝藏？
So, I heard they found silverware in Seabed Palace.
那么 在海底的宫殿找到了银制餐具
So it's true, right?
原来是真的啊
I guess it's true.
应该是真的吧
What's Seabed Palace?
海底宫殿是？
See that uninhabited island over there?
你看 那边不是有座无人小岛吗？
That's Yorioya Island.
那是赖亲岛
(Yorioya Island) 200 meters east of that island,
从那里向东200公尺的海底
there's a sunken huge stone building in the seabed.
有一座已经沉没的巨石建筑物
People say there are ancient ruins near Koumi Island.
在神海岛附近有古遗迹的话题
It's been rumored since about 10 years ago.
从大约10年前就开始传出来了
Many scholars have investigated it,
虽然很多的学者都调查过
but there is no conclusion as to
但是对于它是人为的还是自然形成的
whether it is man-made or natural.
到现在似乎还没有结论
It is said that the part of Yorioya Island that used to be exposed above water was larger before.
听说赖亲岛以前露出海面的部份比现在还大
About 300 years ago, earthquakes caused it to sink into the ocean depths.
大约300年前因为地震沉入海底
That's why it looks like this now.
才会变成我们现在所看到的样子
You said it sank because of earthquakes?
你说是因为地震的原因沉入海底的
Was it like a landslide?
难道是发生了地表滑落吗？
Yeah.
是的
I heard that in the seabed nearby,
听说附近的海底
there's a layer of methane hydrate.
有一种甲烷水合物层
The earthquakes' shaking made it break down in one go,
因为地震的震动让它一口气分解
then caused a landslide.
就造成了地表滑落
That's the most cogent explanation so far..
据说这是最有力的说法了
Hey, Conan. Can you explain for me?
喂 柯南 我问你
What is the "method high tree"?
什么是“假碗水和物曾”
It's "methane hydrate".
是“甲烷水合物层”
In a low temperature and high pressure environment,
在低温高压的环境下
water molecules combine with methane
水分子与甲烷结合
and form the so-called water cage.
形成所谓的水笼结构
It can also be called "combustible ice".
也可以被称为“可燃冰”
Combustible ice?
可燃冰？
Water cage?
水笼结构？
I didn't follow you.
有听没有懂
To put it simply,
简单的说
you've all built castles with playing cards, right?
大家都有用扑克牌盖过城堡吧？
Water molecules build castles just like that.
水分子就像那样盖出城堡
Each room is filled with methane.
每个房间里面装满了甲烷
So when the temperature rises or the pressure falls, it becomes unstable.
所以当温度上升或压力下降就会变得不稳定
The castle will collapse and release methane gas.
城堡就会坍塌并且释放出甲烷气体来
So that's how it works.
原来如此
That's why the island that was held up by methane
所以原本在甲烷上的岛
lost its support and caused a landslide.
就会失去支撑而造成地表滑落啊
That's kind of what I meant.
简单说起来就是这个意思
They talked about it on TV last time.
上次电视上有介绍过
Oh, I see.
哦 原来如此啊
What an idiot.
真是笨蛋
Excuse me, Mima-san.
不好意思 美马先生
This is Iwanaga from the Tourism Division.
我是观光课的岩永
Mima-san, are you there?
美马先生 你在吗？
(Koumi Inn) Mima-san?
美马先生
It's a lot different from the hotel.
和刚才的旅馆差好多啊
You're right.
就是说嘛
I'm sorry, looks like he's not here right now.
不好意思 他好像现在不在
I just tried calling for him.
我给他打完电话了
What's all the noise for? Annoying.
你们在吵什么？吵死人了
Mima-san.
美马先生
These are Mouri-san and his friends, of whom I just mentioned over the phone.
这些人是我刚在电话中提到的毛利先生一行人
Two meals for one night, 5,000 yen.
一个晚上含两餐 5000元
Take it or leave it.
不想住就去别的地方
Wait...Mima-san!
等等…美马先生
What a cocky guy.
这家伙还真跩
Sorry, he's actually very nice.
对不起 其实他人很好的
He's just a little eccentric.
只是脾气有点古怪
Who's going to participate in the treasure hunt?
参加寻宝游戏的有哪几位？
Me!
我！
Two young ladies, are you going to go diving?
两位小姐是要潜水吧？
Yes.
是的
If you want to go right now, I can give you a ride.
如果现在就去的话 可以坐我的车
We'd like that, thank you.
麻烦你了
How about you two?
你们二位呢？
Treasure hunt is really fun.
寻宝游戏很好玩的哦
I want to relax. Don't worry about me.
我想好好放松一下 不用替我担心
How about you, Mouri-san?
毛利先生呢？
Want to participate in treasure...
参加寻宝游戏吗…
No, just tell me where I can get the best local drinks...
不了 告诉我什么店能喝到当地的名酒
and find a pretty hostess there.
又有美女老板娘就可以了
You're Miss Ran Mouri-san and Miss Sonoko Suzuki-san, right?
你们是毛利兰小姐和铃木园子小姐是吧？
You rented the whole set, right?
你们租的是整套装备对吧？
Right.
是的
Kimiko.
喜美子
Coming.
来了
How about these wet suits for both of you?
两位都穿这套潜水衣可以吗？
I think Size M fits you two.
你们穿M的应该就可以了
Okay.
好的
No problem.
没问题
Great.
太好了
Because we don't have a big selection of wet suits here.
因为我们这里的潜水衣种类并不多
No such thing.
才没有呢
This wetsuit looks great.
这套潜水衣看起来很棒呢
Really?
是吗？
Excuse me.
打扰了
You guys, clean up after you're done.
你们几个 用完以后要整理好啊
We'll be back.
我们还会再来的
Those guys are treasure hunters, right?
刚刚那些人是宝藏猎人吧？
Are we going to dive with them?
我们要跟那些人一起潜水吗？
No.
没有
They're just here to borrow the air compressor.
他们只是来借空气压缩机的
There have been more of them these days.
最近这种人变多了
It's really annoying.
让我们很困扰的
Is it related to the discovery of the silverware?
和发现银制餐具有关系吗？
And there's the rumor saying that Anne escaped from prison
再加上还有传闻中越狱的安
and hid the treasure on this island.
把宝藏藏在了这座岛上
Who's Anne?
安是谁？
That's her.
就是那个
270 years ago, during the Kyoho Era of the Edo period,
距今270年以前 江户享保年间
it is said that the entire Seabed Palace was still above water.
传说当时的海底宫殿仍然在海面上
The evidence was the two items found inside Seabed Palace,
证据就是在海底宫殿里面找到的
a cutlass and a pistol.
称作Cutlass的弯刀和手枪
Judging from the initials on the cutlass and the pistol,
根据弯刀和手枪上的缩写判断
These weapons used to belong to two female pirates who were active around 1730,
这个应该是活跃于1730年的两名女海盗
whose names were Anne Bonny and Mary Read.
安·宝妮和玛莉·丽德的武器
They were both led by Captain Jack Rackham...
他们都是杰克·瑞克门船长所带领的…
Female pirates?
女海盗吗？
Yeah.
没错
Anne Bonny and Mary Read.
安·宝妮和玛莉·丽德
They were both pirates under Captain Jack Rackham.
她们都是杰克·瑞克门船长手下的海盗
But when the British came to attack them,
但是当英军来攻击的时候
all the men were hiding below deck,
虽然其他的男人都躲在船舱里面
this two women still fought bravely, back-to-back.
但是她们两个人还是背靠着背英勇的作战
Back to back?
背靠着背啊
That's right. Let your partner to take care of the enemy behind you,
没错 把背后的敌人交给搭档
so that you can concentrate on the enemy in front of you.
自己就能专心的对抗眼前的敌人了
Without this kind of mutual trust, it wouldn't work.
如果没有这样的相互信赖是绝对办不到的
Ran...
小兰
You're the only one I trust to watch my back.
我只愿意把我的背后交给你
Sonoko...
园子…
Just kidding!
开玩笑的
The only one you can trust to watch your back is Shinichi-kun, right?
你是想把背后交给新一对吧？
Who cares about that guy?
谁管那家伙啊
Really?
真的吗？
Really!
是真的啦
Anne, who escaped from a prison in the Bahamas,
从巴哈马监狱逃出来的安
moved her activities to the Pacific Ocean.
把活动的范围移到了太平洋
She continued as a pirate
一边当着海盗
while waiting for Mary to escape from prison as well.
一面等待着玛莉越狱的消息
Later, this story was confirmed.
后来也得到了证实
That's why it was rumored that the treasure they stole together
所以才传出两人一起抢来的宝藏
had been hidden on this Koumi Island.
现在就藏在这座神海岛上
Everyone, let's look for Anne and Mary's hidden treasure!
大家快来寻找安和玛莉藏的宝藏吧
Can this be true?
这种东西会是真的吗？
I don't know.
不清楚
If it's true, this will definitely cause a lot of trouble.
如果是真的 那就不得了了
Maybe it's just a fabrication
搞不好是为了宣传这座岛
to publicize the island.
所捏造出来的东西吧？
If so, it will cause even more trouble.
如果这样就更不得了了
Looks like it's troublesome either way.
不管怎样 问题都非同小可
Sorry, sorry.
抱歉抱歉
Sorry to keep you waiting.
让大家久等了
Hey, hey...
喂…喂…
Here, this is a map for the treasure hunt.
来 这个是寻宝地图
Starting from here,
从这里开始
you need to go to each of 5 points hidden on the map, press the seal,
到隐藏在地图中的5个地方盖上印章
and then solve the puzzle.
然后解开谜题
The first point is there.
首先第一个地方是那里
Take the seal there and press it on the blank space at the bottom of the map,
把放在那里的印章盖到地图下方的空白处
then take a hint card for the next point
再从旁边的宝箱中
from the treasure chest next to it.
拿出写着下个地点提示的卡片
It simply is a trick for kids.
简直就是骗小孩
Don't say that.
别这么说嘛
They look very enthusiastic about it.
他们可是干劲十足的啊
10 and 12.
10和12
This is the key to the location of the treasure.
这就是提示宝藏地点的关键啊
The next point is...
下一个地点是…
"Even if the sun doesn't set, a pirate still shines."
“即使夕阳不落 海盗仍旧闪耀”
What's this?
这个是什么啊？
Go for it!
好好加油吧
If you find where the treasure is,
如果找到宝藏所在的地方
you'll get a special gift.
还可以得到特别的礼物喔
Is that special gift something to eat?
那个特别礼物是吃的东西吗？
You'll know when you solve the mystery.
谜题揭晓了以后就自然会知道了
Okay, I'll work really hard for it!
好 我要加油了
You don't know if it's something to eat yet.
还不知道是不是吃的东西喔
Hey, Uncle.
大叔
What is it?
什么事？
Did you come up with all these codes yourself?
这些暗号都是你想出来的吧？
Ah? You can say that.
啊 算是吧
Oh, right.
对了
You can rent bikes at the district office next door.
隔壁的区公所里面可以出租脚踏车
Why don't you take bikes?
你们骑着脚踏车去吧
You'll be tired if you walk.
如果用走的话会很累的
Yes!
好！
Looks like you're enthusiastic too, Kudo-kun.
干劲十足呢 工藤
Okay, all set!
好了 准备完毕
Now, just follow Kimiko's instructions.
现在你们就听从喜美子的指示吧
Enjoy a safe, fun dive!
安全的享受潜水乐趣吧
Pay special attention to the area south of Seabed Palace.
要特别注意海底宫殿的南边
It's very deep over there.
那边很深的
Please don't scare us.
请不要吓我们啦
It's okay, I'll be with you.
没关系 有我在
Indeed.
这倒也是
Thank you for that!
拜托你了
So quick.
这么快
Did something happen?
发生什么事了吗？
Sharks!
有鲨鱼！
Because that hint mentioned the sunset,
因为提示中有提到夕阳
we came to the far west side of the island.
所以到了岛上的最西边
But where is the treasure chest mentioned by that hint?
但是 提示的宝箱在什么地方呢？
Oh! I see!
原来如此 我明白了！
The hint was "even if the sun doesn't set, a pirate still shines", right?
提示是“即使夕阳不落 海盗仍旧闪耀”吧？
So that must be...
所以那一定是…
The surface of the sea!
海面！
I see.
原来如此
Then what?
然后呢？
Is it possible that there is a seal on the surface of the sea?
海面上有可能会放印章吗？
Ah, that's not possible, indeed...
啊 的确不可能…
That's right...
是啊…
Look over there.
你们看那里
What's that?
那是什么啊？
It's a large school of fish!
是鱼群耶
Are they eels?
该不会是鳗鱼吧？
There won't be any eel in this kind of place.
这种地方是不会有鳗鱼的
So that's how it is.
原来如此啊
Hey, Conan!
喂 柯南
What do you mean by "so that's how it is"?
你说的“原来如此”是什么意思啊？
Did you find anything?
你知道什么了吗？
Do you know why the fish are gathering together?
你们知道为什么鱼会聚集在一起呢？
Why...
为什么…
Because they want to play together?
是大家想一起玩吗？
Or perhaps because they are hungry and want to eat something together?
是因为肚子饿了一起吃东西吧？
Bingo!
答对了
Then, what is it that fish eat?
那鱼的食物又是什么呢？
Plankton?
浮游生物吗？
Correct.
答对了
Awesome!
好壮观喔
What's down here?
这里有什么东西呢？
Look.
你们看
It's sea fireflies!
海萤火虫是夜行性生物，在夜间依靠自身发出的生物光指引同类聚集寻找食物，群居 是海萤火虫呀
Right! "Even if the sun doesn't set, a pirate still shines."
对呀“即使夕阳不落 海盗仍旧闪耀”
That's what it means.
就是指这里啊
Found it.
找到了
"Thin pirates will laugh."
“瘦的海盗会笑”
Even fat pirates can laugh, can't they?
即使不是瘦的也会笑吧
What's wrong, Haibara?
怎么了？灰原
Someone in a wet suit, covered in blood, was just carried away.
刚刚有个穿潜水衣的人满身是血的被抬走了
What?
什么？
I don't know if it's Ran-san, though.
虽然还不知道是不是小兰
Conan-kun!
柯南
I need to leave with Edogawa-kun for a while.
我和江户川先离开一下子
You guys just go ahead.
你们继续寻宝吧
Haibara-san is leaving too.
连灰原也跑了
Don't worry.
不用担心
I'm still here with you.
还有我在呢
Let's find the treasure by ourselves.
我们靠自己找出宝藏吧
You're right.
也对
Ran-nee-chan!
小…小兰姐姐
Conan-kun?
柯南
Ai-chan is here too?
小哀也来了啊
Are you... Are you okay?
你…你没有事吧？
We're fine.
我们倒没有事
How is it? Officer Uehira?
情况怎么样了？上平警官
Kimiko-chan.
喜美子
Kimiko-chan, were you there too when it happened?
喜美子 事发时你也在场吗？
No.
没有
I was diving with my clients nearby.
我刚好带客人在附近潜水
But I was really shocked back then.
但是 真的是吓了我一跳
I saw that shark attacking a person.
竟然看见鲨鱼在攻击人
There were actually three people there.
而且明明有三个人在
But only one was attacked.
但被攻击却只有一个人
What do you mean?
你是什么意思？
Nothing.
没什么
But it's really troublesome.
不过 还真是伤脑筋呀
It's been a long time since sharks attacked people.
已经有很长时间没发生过鲨鱼攻击人的意外了
Speaking of which,
话说回来
that's the first time I've seen sharks at that spot.
我还是在那里第一次看到鲨鱼呢
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Kimiko-san said that there were three of them diving together,
喜美子说当时是三个人一起潜水的
but only one was attacked.
但却只有一人遭到攻击
You don't think it was an accident?
你认为不是偶然吗？
Since those guys are professionals,
那些人既然是专家
they should at least know how to deal with sharks.
至少应该知道对付鲨鱼的办法
Did you find anything?
你发现了什么吗？
A plastic bag.
是塑胶袋
Fish blood?
是鱼血吗？
So this must be the cause.
这个应该就是原因所在
Right.
没错
Someone put fish blood in a thin plastic bag,
那鱼的血装进薄塑胶袋中
sealed it well and then hid it inside the buoyancy control jacket.
轻轻封住后在藏入潜浮力衣里面
Underwater, atmospheric pressure increases by one for every 10 meters.
水深每增加10公尺就会增加1气压
Sea lever is at 1 atmospheric pressure.
在海面上就是1大气压
It becomes 2 atmospheric pressure when you dive 10 meters.
潜10公尺就会变成2大气压
When you get to 30 meters, it becomes 4.
潜30公尺就是4大气压了
With such a high water pressure,
如果承受这么大的水压
the plastic bag's seal will definitely be broken.
塑胶袋的封口一定会破裂
Sharks can hear sounds from miles away.
鲨鱼能听见数公里以外的声音
Even if the blood is diluted a million times,
即使将血液稀释百万倍
with their sense of smell, they can still smell it.
凭他们的嗅觉也能够闻得到
This is a murder case...
这是杀人案件…
Yes.
是啊
Although it's still an attempted murder yet.
目前还是未遂就是了
Hey, brat with glasses!
喂 戴眼镜的小鬼
What are you two doing sneaking around here?
你们俩在这里偷偷摸摸的干什么呢？
There's a case, Uncle Mouri.
发生案件了 大叔
What?
什么？
Why didn't they inform me...
为什么没有通知我…
I'm the famous detective Kogoro Mouri, after all.
我这个名侦探毛利小五郎
This shark's mouth is really big.
这鲨鱼的嘴巴还真大啊
But he was just bitten by a shark.
只不过是被鲨鱼咬
It's not a case, but an accident, isn't it?
这不是案件 是意外吧？
What are you fussing about?
你在啊什么啊？
What is this?
这是什么？
How's it going, Doctor?
怎么样了 医生？
We did everything we could.
我们已经尽力了
But because he bled too much...
但是因为出血过多…
I'm so sorry for your loss.
请节哀顺变
Damn it!
可恶！
How could this happen?
怎么会变成这样
Why would there be an accidental death here?
竟然会发生死亡意外
No, it wasn't an accident.
不 这不是什么意外
You're the famous detective...
你是名侦探…
Kogoro Mouri.
毛利小五郎
Dad?
爸爸
Uncle.
叔叔
Hey, why did you say it wasn't an accident?
喂 你说这不是意外到底是怎么回事？
Someone lured sharks to attack you on purpose.
有人故意引鲨鱼来攻击你们
Someone put a plastic bag full of fish blood
这件浮力衣里面被人放入了
in this buoyancy control jacket.
装满鱼血的塑胶袋
By the way, given that you are all treasure hunters,
对了 听说你们都是宝藏猎人
things can't be that simple, right?
事情应该不会这么单纯吧？
Ran-nee-chan.
小兰姐姐
Where are the buoyancy control jackets usually kept?
通常浮力衣都会放在什么地方？
Well...
这个嘛…
Usually, we won't take them back to the hotel rooms.
一般来说不会把它带回旅馆房间去
I think people around here will send them to the diving stops,
这一带应该是寄放在潜水店吧
and fill their oxygen tanks there too.
顺便请他们把氧气筒充气
If someone wants to tamper with this buoyancy control jacket,
如果要在这件浮力衣上动手脚的话
it should be here.
应该是在这里吧？
It would be too risky to do it after someone's already taken it out.
等拿出去了再动手脚风险就太大了
Hey, Kudo-kun!
喂 工藤
What is it, Haibara?
怎么了 灰原？
Look at this.
你看这个
People usually wash away the seawater from the instruments here,
因为在这里冲掉器具上的海水
so this place is always damp.
所以一直很潮湿呢
Sorry, can you take some pictures with this for me?
不好意思 你帮我用这个拍一下吧
I still have other things to investigate.
我还有别的需要调查的事情
Since when did I become your assistant?
唉呀 我什么时候变成你的助手了？
No, not an assistant. You're more like my partner.
不 不能说是助手 应该说是搭档吧
That's a nice way of putting it.
真会说漂亮话
Then, I'm counting on you.
那拜托你了
All right.
好 好
Hey, onee-san.
大姐姐
What is it?
什么事？
Is there anyone in this shop at night?
晚上这家店有人在吗？
Oh, you're playing a detective game, right?
啊 你玩侦探游戏啊
My house is right behind this shop.
我家就在这家店后面
Kimiko lives in an apartment near the port.
喜美子就住在港口附近的公寓里
So there's no one here at night.
所以晚上这里没人
I see.
这样啊
And since there are no thieves on this island,
而且这座岛上没有什么小偷
we usually don't lock the door.
所以平常我们也不锁门的
Kimiko, you were in charge of closing the shop last night, right?
喜美子 昨晚是你关店的吧？
Yes, why do you ask?
是啊 怎么了？
Because this little detective asked me a lot of questions.
因为这位小侦探同学向我打听了很多事情
I see.
原来是这样
You're investigating who could have done something to that buoyancy control jacket, right?
你是在调查那件浮力衣是谁做的手脚对吧？
Mhm.
嗯
I closed the shop last night and opened it this morning.
昨天晚上的确是我关店 早上来开店的也是我
But since the door was unlocked,
不过因为一直没上锁
anyone could have snuck in and done something.
谁都可以溜进来动手脚的
How is it?
怎么样
Do you have any clues?
有什么线索吗？
No.
没有
We haven't found anything yet...
到现在还什么都没发现…
I hope you can find something.
能找到就好了呢
What's wrong?
怎么了？
How can you have the nerve to ask what's wrong?
你还好意思问怎么了
What are you doing, Conan?
你在搞什么啊 柯南？
We can't find pirates' treasure without you!
你不来的话海盗的宝藏就找不到了啦
You guys should try to use your brains once in a while.
你们偶尔也试着自己解解看啊
We can't find it on our own!
靠我们几个是找不到的啦
Where are you right now?
你们现在在哪？
We're heading to a hanging bridge.
正往吊桥那边去呢
Hanging bridge?
吊桥？
It's drawn on the treasure map.
画在寻宝地图上的啊
The treasure map...
寻宝地图啊…
Okay, I found it.
啊 找到了找到了
Hurry up and get over here!
那快点过来喔
Got it.
知道啦
I guess I have no choice.
真没办法
Hey, Haibara. Wanna come with me?
喂 灰原 要一起去吗？
I'm not going.
我不去
I knew it.
我就知道
Hey, what is this?
喂喂 这算什么啊
The way is completely blocked.
根本就没有路嘛
Geez...
真是的
Hey, are you here alone?
喂 你一个人吗？
Yeah.
嗯
I think they're still by the hanging bridge up there.
我想他们应该还在上面的吊桥那里
That's where I want to go.
我就是想去那里
But there's a prohibitory traffic sign there.
不过那里有个禁止通行的牌子
Sorry, sorry.
啊 抱歉抱歉
Last week, an earthquake caused a landslide which blocked the road.
上星期因为地震造成土石崩落把路给堵住了
If you go a little further,
再往前走一点的话
you'll find a pathway that turns left.
应该有条向左转的小路
Can you use that pathway?
能从那条路绕过去吗？
Mhm.
嗯
Thank you, Iwanaga-san.
谢谢你 岩永先生
Be careful, then.
那小心点哦
Okay!
好的
That's enough. I don't know the answer.
已经够了啦 我猜不出来了啦
Conan-kun will be here soon. It will be fine.
柯南快来了 没关系的
It's okay even if Conan-kun is not here.
就算柯南不在也没关系的啊
We can solve this puzzle ourselves.
我们自己来解谜吧
Ah, there seems to be a sign on the other side of the bridge.
啊 吊桥那边好像有个牌子喔
What is it?
是什么呢？
Let's go check it out.
过去看看吧
I'm hungry.
肚子饿了
Hey, wait for me!
喂 等等我啦
Wait a minute!
等一下
Don't move!
不要乱动！
Why...why?
为…为什么
This... this is...
这…这是
Warning: Passage forbidden to anyone who weighs over 40 kilograms.
注意：禁止体重40公斤以上的人通行
What is going on?
到底怎么回事啊
Genta-kun, how much do you weigh?
元太 你多重啊？
39 kilograms!
39公斤
Lying!
骗人
I've put on a little weight. Maybe 45 kilograms...
稍微胖了点 45公斤吧…
You can't come over here.
不能过来
This hanging bridge will break if someone over 40 kilograms crosses it!
这座吊桥 40公斤的人通过的话就会断掉的
Are you serious?
真…真的假的啊！？
So that's it! I see!
这样啊 我明白了
Thin pirates will laugh. It's telling us to walk across this hanging bridge, right?
瘦的海盗会笑 就是让我们走过这座吊桥吧？
Right!
对耶
Thin pirates will laugh, that is to say, a fat pirate will cry.
瘦的海盗会笑 也就是说胖的海盗会哭啊
Help me, Mama!
救命啊 妈妈
Found it.
找到了
What does "pirates never cry" mean?
“海盗不哭”是什么意思呢？
It's already 4:00.
已经4点了
Let's continue tomorrow.
明天再继续吧
Yeah, but how do we get back?
嗯 但是该怎么回去呢？
Yeah.
是啊
If Genta keeps squatting there,
如果元太在那里趴着
once we step on,
我们两个人再上去
this hanging bridge will definitely break.
吊桥一定会断掉的
Hey, what are you doing?
喂 你们在干什么啊？
Conan-kun, we found it!
柯南 我们找到了喔
Well done. Not bad for you!
真厉害 很能干嘛
The next hint is "pirates never cry"!
下一个提示是“海盗不哭”
But this bridge
但是这座桥
will break if someone who weighs over 40 kilograms goes across it.
如果40公斤以上的人通过的话
He might fall off!
好像会掉下去的样子
Is that what is written on that sign?
上面是这么写的吗？
No.
不是
What's written on it is "passage forbidden to anyone who weighs over 40 kilograms".
上面是写 禁止40公斤以上的人通行
I see.
原来如此
That's why "thin pirates will laugh".
所以才是“瘦的海盗会笑”啊
It's okay. You can walk through.
没关系 你们尽管走过来吧
That sign is just a hint.
那块牌子只是个提示
The only people who could weigh under 40 kilograms are women and children.
40公斤以下的人 不是小孩就是女人
There can't be a code that only these people can solve.
不可能存在只有这些人才能解开的暗号的
Thank you for coming, Inspector!
辛苦了 警官
But did you have to come all the way here...
但是还要劳烦警官亲自跑一趟…
Because I found some aspects to be weird...
因为我觉得有些地方很怪…
Inspector...
警…警官
Thank you for coming all the way here.
麻烦您远道而来 辛苦了
I'd like to know all of the details.
我想先了解一下状况
Understood!
我明白了
You treat us like we're criminals.
简直就是把我们当成犯人一样
We are victims, aren't we?
我们应该是受害者吧？
If you really are the victim...
如果真是受害者
then tell us the truth like a real victim would do!
就像个受害者的样子老实点说怎么样？
Have you ever seen these two people?
你们有见过这两个人吗？
Well... I've never seen them before.
这个嘛… 都没有见过啊
These two men attacked a supermarket in Shinbashi last night.
这两人昨天晚上袭击了新桥的超市
and took all the cash from the store.
把店里的现金都抢走了
They said you told them to do so, as an initiation to join your group.
你们说是受到你们的指使 为了想要加入你们
How could I know?
我怎么知道
I think they were just talking nonsense to get rid of you police.
应该是为了脱罪胡说八道的吧
You bastard!
你这家伙
Do you have any evidence? Evidence!
你有证据吗？证据！
All you have is only the testimony of those two people, right?
只有那两人的证词不是吗？
All right, all right.
好啦好啦
Calm down, everyone.
大家先冷静一下
Let's have some refreshing drinks now.
先喝些清凉的饮料吧
Well, if there are no other questions,
那么 如果没有什么其他问题的话
I'd like to return to my room and get some rest.
我想先回房休息了
You really don't know who might want to kill you?
你们真的不知道盯上你们的人是谁吗？
Matsumoto-san.
松本先生
I really don't know.
没有呢
Bye, then.
再见啦
Excuse me, can I borrow a match?
那个 抱歉 可以借根火柴吗？
I forgot my lighter.
我忘记带打火机了
Here.
拿去
Oh, thanks.
啊 谢谢
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
Alas, what a waste of time!
啊 真是浪费时间啊
Can I have a sip of that?
那个 我可以喝一口吗？
I'm a little thirsty.
口有点渴了
It's okay. They didn't touch them at all.
没关系 他们完全没碰过
I thought we could get their fingerprints.
本以为可以采集到指纹的
Yeah.
是啊
But even if we could get their fingerprints,
不过就算能够采集到指纹
it's gonna take a lot of time
在这座岛上要等到结果出来
to get the results on this island,
也是要花不少时间
regardless of whether we got someone to come analyze them or sent them back for testing.
不管是鉴识人员过来 或是送回去鉴识
But then again, Takagi-kun...
这么说来 高木
Do you smoke?
你有抽烟吗？
I'm sorry.
不好意思
Do you have three-second glue?
有三秒胶吗？
What should we do when we have a meal?
吃饭的时候要做什么呢？
lame quiz?
冷笑话猜谜
Answered correctly.
答对了
Here you go again.
出现了啊
You're gonna do this now?
现在才开始啊
I knew it's about time for this.
我想差不多也该开始了吧
In the fish kingdom near the ruins on the seabed,
在海底遗迹旁的鱼的王国里
because the evil deeds of the previous king were revealed,
因为前任国王做的坏事被发现了
the sea bream became the next king.
所以让鲷鱼继任国王
So which of the following was the previous king?
那么前任的国王是下面的哪一个呢？
1. Squid.
1.乌贼
2. Octopus.
2.章鱼
3. Crab.
3.螃蟹
So, which one is it?
那么 到底是那个呢？
Ah, I got it.
啊 我知道了
It's the third one! Crab!
是3的螃蟹
Why?
为什么呢？
It cut off the heads of those ones it hated with its pincers.
它把看不顺眼的家伙的头用夹子给剪掉了
That was too much!
真过分
Don't be ridiculous.
不要乱讲啦
Well, it seems to be a bit cruel.
似乎是有点残忍啊
Sorry...
对不起
It's the octopus, right?
是章鱼吧？
Oh, so why is that?
哦 那又是为什么呢？
The king octopus took all the kingdom's property for itself.
章鱼国王将国家的财产独占了
Imagine how an octopus looks.
请想像一下章鱼的外表
That is to say, baldies make a lot of money, right?
原文为“坊主丸储け（ぼうずまるもうけ）”  原意是指靠赚死人的钱发财的和尚，后来引申为不劳而获 就是说“光头赚大钱”是吧？
Right!
就是这样
But I don't think that's a right answer.
这应该不对吧？
Then it's the first choice, squid!
那我猜1号的乌贼
Well, why?
嗯 为什么呢
Please leave it to me!
请交给我
I'll answer correctly this time!
我这次一定会答对的
The king (osama) can be split into "o" and "sama".
国王陛下可以拆成国王和陛下
If it was squid (ika), it would be "ika" and "sama".
如果是乌贼的话 就是乌贼和陛下
Ika-sama...
就是乌贼陛下
Ikasama?
乌贼陛下
-So it means cheat!
日语里乌贼叫いか，陛下是さま，而连起来读的いかさま就是作弊的意思 所以是作弊的意思
That's correct...
正…正确答案
There is something fishy...
好可疑啊
Ah, Conan-kun...
啊 柯南…
The King is squid, which means "ikasama". The evil deeds are its cheat, that's why squid is the king.
国王陛下是乌贼，就是乌贼陛下，就是说作弊是坏事，所以才是乌贼当国王
This is the real...
这就是真正的…
Cheat.
作弊
What a beautiful moon!
好美的月亮啊
Forgive me for my rudeness, but why would you provide lodging to tourists at your house?
恕我冒昧 为什么美马先生会经营民宿呢？
Actually, I can make a living by fishing.
其实我一个人生活 靠捕鱼也能过的去
The district office asked me to provide lodging.
民宿是区公所说要开的
I heard that it was because they wanted to attract more tourists.
听说是想要招揽观光的客人
I see.
原来如此
Maybe we're interfering with your life.
我们或许打扰了你们的生活也说不定呢
It's better to have you stay than those treasure hunters.
比起宝藏猎人你们要好的多了
Speaking of treasure hunters,
说起宝藏猎人
is there really treasure here?
这里真的有宝藏吗？
Coyotes don't gather where there is no prey,
土狼不会聚集在没有猎物的地方
although it may not be the prey they're expecting.
虽然那未必是它所要的猎物
I don't know!
我不知道啦
Why do pirates never cry?
什么“海盗不哭”啊
Try to think about it carefully, Genta-kun.
你认真一点想啦 元太
Hey, kids!
喂 小鬼
"Pirates never cry" is a hint?
“海盗不哭”是提示吗？
Yeah, that's right.
是这样没错
I'd know the answer if it was "pirates cry".
如果是“海盗哭泣”我倒知道
"Pirates cry"?
“海盗哭泣”吗？
Maybe there's a hint there.
或许会有什么线索呢
Do you want to take a look now?
要不要现在去看看？
Are you going out at this hour?
现在还出门吗？
It's already dark outside. Why don't you go tomorrow?
外面已经很暗了喔 明天再去吧…
Nobody knows if the weather will change tomorrow.
明天的天气还很难说喔
You mean it's going to get worse?
你是说会变差啰
When the south wind starts blowing, we don't go fishing.
开始吹南风的时候 我们就不会出海捕鱼了
The waves might get very violent.
风浪或许会变得很大
That is the life knowledge, right?
这就是生活的智慧对吧？
Then let's go together. It can be an after-dinner walk.
那大家一起去吧 就当作饭后散步
Okay.
好
What are you going to do, Takagi-kun?
你打算怎么做呢 高木？
It's called cyanoacrylate
这个叫做氰丙烯酸酯法
The vapor of butyl acrylate of isocyanuric acid, a component of three-second glue,
这是利用三秒胶的成分异氰尿酸的丙烯酸丁酯蒸汽
reacts to the water in the secretion. It can help us to collect fingerprints.
会对分泌物中的水分产生反应的特性来采集指纹的方法
Then, just wait for a while,
然后只要再等一段时间
the fingerprints will emerge themselves.
指纹就应该会自己浮现出来
When did you learn this method?
你是什么时候学会这种方法的？
Actually, I saw it in a movie one time.
不是啦 以前在看过的电影里有这招
Then I confirmed it with the Forensics Officer Tome.
后来和登米鉴识官确认过了
Well, I hope this works as smoothly as it did in the movie.
嗯 要是能和电影里一样顺利当然是最好了
Is this where the answer of "pirates never cries" hides?
那个海盗不哭的答案就在这里吗？
I'm not sure about the answer.
答案我不是很清楚
But the crying place is here.
不过哭泣的话就是在这里
Crying...
哭泣
Could it be the sound of the wind?
会不会是风的声音呢？
It sounds like someone crying.
听起来挺像哭声的
Wow, really.
哦 真的耶
I heard it on the way here, too.
到这里来的路上也听得到喔
I knew that already.
这我当然知道
The sand here contains a lot of quartz.
这里的沙子很多石英的成分呢
And the sand is fine too.
而且沙粒也很细小
I see.
原来如此
Hey, Conan!
喂 柯南
Did you find out anything?
你知道什么了吗？
Listen carefully.
你们好好听着
Ah, so it is singing sand! It sounds crying!
啊 原来是哭沙啊
So, that's why "pirates cry"!
这样啊 所以才是“海盗哭泣”啊
You'll have to figure out the rest on your own.
接下来就要你们自己去想了
Got it.
我知道
Next is "pirates never cry", right?
接下来 是“海盗不哭”是吧？
Could it be there?
是那个啊
Come on! There is no sound here!
过来吧 这里就是不哭的地方了
So there is where pirates never cry, right?
那里就是海盗不哭的地方了吧？
They created a good atmosphere.
设计的真有气氛
The next one is "souls of pirates will go to heaven".
接下来是“海盗的灵魂会升天”啊
Another inexplicable hint.
又是莫名其妙的东西
But the head of the Tourism Division does have a rich imagination.
不过他还真能想啊 那个观光课长
The head of the Tourism Division, Iwanaga-san.
观光课长岩永先生啊
Didn't he say he came up with these codes himself?
他不是说这些暗号都是他想的吗？
That's his job, that's all, right?
这本来就是他的工作吧？
Such a killjoy...
真是个不浪漫的家伙
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Conan-kun, what's wrong?
柯南 怎么了？
Things are getting interesting.
越来越有意思了
Conan-kun?
柯南？
Sorry, I need to go somewhere.
抱歉 我有个地方要去
You guys go back first.
你们先回去吧
Wait, Conan!
等等 柯南
Not again...
又来了啊
This brat has no team spirit at all.
这小鬼真是完全没有团队精神啊
Conan-kun...
柯南…
Here it is!
出现了
Now we just have to change it into data and send it by email, then we'll know the results.
接下来只要做成资料 用电子邮件传送过去就能知道结果了
Good job, Takagi-kun!
干得好 高木
Nothing...
哪里
If you ever want to transfer to the Identification Division, just let me know.
如果你想调去鉴识课就尽管说一声
If you don't mind, I can write a recommendation letter for you.
不介意的话 我可以给你写推荐信哦
Please don't joke with me.
饶了我吧
Anyway, let's send it back to headquarters.
总之先传回本部吧
Got it!
我知道了
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
I got lost while taking a walk.
刚才散步的时候迷路了
Could you please tell me where Koumi Inn is?
请问神海庄在哪里？
That way.
在那里
Thank you. Good night.
谢谢 晚安
How's it going, Takagi-kun?
怎么样了 高木？
Have you heard back from headquarters?
本部那边有回覆吗？
No, not yet.
不 还没有
I see...
这样啊…
What... What's wrong?
怎…怎么了？
The alarm in the Tourism Museum has gone off!
观光馆的警铃响了
So there must be something happened in the Tourism Museum.
就是说观光馆出事了吗？
Actually, the alarm here often malfunctions...
那个 其实这里的警铃经常故障…
Just in case, let's check it out there!
不管怎么说先去看看 以防万一
Where is it?
地点呢？
Right next to the district office.
就在区公所旁边
Borrow us your car.
车子借我一用
Sure.
啊 好
Headquarters might send a report back later.
本部应该会有报告传来
Please take care of it for us.
就拜托你了
I got it.
我知道了
Geez, why are there so many incidents happening these days?
真是的 为什么这样的事件一个接一个啊
Oh, coming!
啊 来了
Well...
那个…
This is...
这…这个是…
Get in!
快上车
What I asked for is stores with beautiful hostesses.
我问的是有没有美女老板娘或是漂亮妈妈桑的店啊
Geez!
真是的
Can't I have a drink in peace?
就不能让我安静的喝酒吗？
That's why I hate tourist spots that much!
就是这样我才讨厌观光景点的
I'm going to get angry!
本大爷要生气了
Hey, can't you just shut up!
喂 吵死啦
Ah? What's wrong?
啊 怎么啦？
Hey, wait a minute!
喂 等一下
What are you doing?
你想干什么啊？
How could you tell me this is the store with beautiful hostess?
这里哪是有美女老板娘的店啊？
Head of the Tourism Division!
观光课长
What does it matter?
有什么关系嘛
She'll look beautiful when she's in a dark room!
稍微暗一点的地方看 就是个美女嘛
You're responsible for this!
我要你负责
I'm very busy right now!
我现在很忙的
Why?
为什么啊？
A thief broke into the exhibition room of the museum!
有小偷闯进观光馆的展览室里
What?
什么？
A thief?
小偷？
Get out of the way!
让开
Wait a minute.
等一下
Get on!
快点坐上来
Or I'll go without you!
不上来就丢下你了喔
Hold on, please...
等…等一下
Hold on tight! I'm going to go fast!
抓紧了 要冲了哦
Wait, you haven't paid yet! Customer!
等一下 还没付钱呢 这位客人
What happened, old lady?
怎么了 老婆婆？
Uehira-chan, a man didn't pay his bill! Please catch him for me!
上平先生 有人吃霸王餐 帮我抓住他
Geez... Another incident?
真是的 又有案件了啊
They broke the display counter and stole the display items.
竟然打破展示柜抢走展示品
That was a bold move.
好大胆
How is it, Sato-kun?
怎么样 佐藤？
Just as Conan-kun said, there are signs of gunshots.
正如柯南所说的 有遭到枪击的痕迹
There are still blood stains at the scene.
现场还遗留着血迹
I see.
这样啊
Can you protect the scene?
有办法保护现场吗？
It would be a little difficult.
有点困难呢
I guess so.
我想也是啊
Anyway, take pictures of the crime scene and then come back here.
总之先把现场照片拍下来 然后再回到这里
Got it.
我知道了
The cutlass and the pistol were stolen!
弯刀和手枪被偷走了
Are they something valuable?
是很有价值的东西吗？
They were precious items found inside Seabed Palace.
是海底宫殿里发现的宝贝
Anne Bonny's cutlass and Mary Read's pistol.
是安·宝妮的弯刀和玛莉·丽德的手枪
There's nothing to worry about! I can handle it!
有我在就没有什么可以担心的了
Mouri, your face is so red!
毛利 你的脸好红啊
No...
哪里哪里
That's because everyone is here...
那是因为大家都在这里…
Kogoro Mouri, you're under arrest!
毛利小五郎 我要逮捕你
I'm arresting you for not paying your bill, stealing a bicycle and riding it while drunk!
以吃霸王餐 抢夺脚踏车 酒后驾车的现行犯的罪名…
Hey, hey...
喂喂
Is that true?
那是真的吗？
Yes.
是啊
He didn't pay his bill at the pub,
他在酒馆喝了酒没付钱
stole Iwanaga-san's bicycle and fled.
还抢了岩永先生的脚踏车逃走
That's what the hostess of that pub told me.
这是酒馆的老板娘说的
I didn't steal and flee!
我才没有抢了就逃
The head of the Tourism Division was sitting right behind me!
观光课长不就坐在我后面吗？
Right? Right?
对吧 对吧
Yes...yes.
是…是啊
Oh right, Inspector. The results of the fingerprint analyzation arrived.
对了 警部先生 指纹比照的结果传来了
Hey, is this true?
喂 这是真的吗？
Mitsushi Matsumoto
松本光次
He has stolen important cultural artifacts from ruins all over the world,
曾在世界各地的遗迹、博物馆等地
along with committing theft and burglary of works of art, and even murder.
抢夺美术品、出土品 还犯有杀人罪
He's a big fish.
他可是条大鱼呢
So they're international fugitives.
原来他们是国际通缉犯啊
They're here for Anne and Mary's treasure.
安和玛莉的宝藏果然被盯上了
What do you mean by that?
被盯上了是什么意思？
There's more treasure besides the stolen cutlass and pistol?
宝藏难道不是只有被偷走的手枪和弯刀吗？
Ah, yeah.
啊 是的
Anne Bonny and Mary Read were female pirates.
安·宝妮和玛莉·丽德曾是女海盗
Legend has it that three hundred years ago,
传说活跃于三百年前的他们
they hid their treasure on this Koumi Island.
将宝藏藏在这座神海岛上
Is it true that they hid their treasure here?
他们的宝藏真的在这里？
Yes.
对
The stolen pistol and cutlass are the best proof.
被偷走的手枪和弯刀就是证据
Hey, uncle, didn't you go to the store with the beautiful hostess?
对了叔叔 你没去有美女老板娘的店吗？
It was not a store with a beautiful hostess.
根本就不是有美女老板娘的店
What's worse, it was just a store with an old hag.
只是有个欧巴桑的店罢了
As expected...
果然
It's that smell.
果然是这个味道
Uncle, you've got something on you.
叔叔 你沾到东西了喔
What is this?
这是什么啊？
I see.
原来如此
How do you get off of this island?
从这个岛上离开的方法是什么？
There's only one scheduled ship every afternoon.
因为每天下午只有一班定期航班
Apart from that, the only way to leave here is taking a fishing boat.
除了渔船以外没有离开的方法
Good.
好
Ask everyone to be extra careful
为了避免渔船被抢
to avoid having their fishing boats stolen.
请通知大家注意
I...I got it.
我…我知道了
Hey, what about these handcuffs?
喂 这个手铐怎么办啊？
Hey...
喂…
Well... Inspector Megure.
那个 目暮警官
That Matsumoto guy...
那个叫松本的人
I saw that he paying off the diving shop owner, Mabuchi-san.
好像有拿钱给那个潜水店的老板马渊喔
What?
什么？
Inspector Megure, we're back.
目暮警官 我们回来了
Thank you for your hard work.
辛苦了
Sorry, but there's another task I need you to do right away.
不好意思还有件马上要办的事
The diving shop owner seems to have some contact with Matsumoto.
潜水店的老板似乎和松本有接触
You two go to the diving shop.
你们两人去一趟潜水店
We're going to the hotel where Matsumoto is staying.
我们要去松本住的旅馆
Yes, sir.
遵命
Inspector, my handcuffs!
警官 我的手铐啊
How's the weather?
天气怎么样？
The wind is strong.
风倒是很大
But the sun is out, so it should be fine.
不过有出太阳 应该没问题吧
Let's zoom in.
放大一下看看
The pattern of the tires is completely different.
轮胎的纹路完全不一样
As suspected, it's not this bike.
果然不是这辆脚踏车啊
Conan-kun.
柯南
Coming!
来了
Conan-kun, the food is ready!
柯南 吃饭了哦
I'll be right there!
马上就来
What is it?
怎么了
It looks like a GPS.
好像是全球定位系统
GPS?
全球定位系统？
Why would it be placed on a bicycle?
为什么装在脚踏车上
Geez, what is Conan doing?
真是的 柯南那家伙到底在搞什么啊
He said he's coming. Just give him a minute.
他说马上就来 再等一下吧
Look, he's here.
你看 他来了
Sorry to keep you waiting.
久等了
Conan, you're so slow! I'm starving!
柯南你很慢耶 肚子都快饿扁了
Sorry, sorry...
抱歉抱歉
Ah, where's Uncle Mouri?
啊 叔叔呢？
He said he had a meeting with the police this morning,
他说早上开始要开搜查会议
so he went down to the district office.
所以去区公所开会了
Well, now that everyone is here.
那既然大家都到齐了
I'm starting!
我开动了
I didn't realize it'd be nearby.
没想到还挺近的呢
Yummy! I want another one!
好好吃 再来一碗
Did you meet Iwanaga-san on the way to the hanging bridge?
那个 你们去吊桥的时候有没有碰到岩永先生呢？
Iwanaga-san?
岩永先生？
Oh, the head of the Tourism Division?
啊 那个观光课长啊
Yeah.
是啊
No, we didn't see him.
没有 没碰到他耶
Right?
是吧？
Right.
对啊
We found that place by ourselves.
那里是我们自己找到的喔
I see...
这样啊
Do you have enough food?
食物的量还够吧？
Yeah, thank you very much.
还够 非常感谢
Are you going for a dive today as well?
你们今天还要去潜水吗？
No, because of what happened yesterday, I'm still a little scared.
不了 因为昨天发生了那样的事情 很害怕
But we may not have much time to have fun tomorrow,
不过 明天可能没时间玩了
so we'd like to go on a boat trip today.
今天想去搭船看看
Better not to go out to sea in the afternoon.
下午最好不要出海
The waves might be very violent.
风浪应该会很大
Really?
果然是这样啊
Then we have to hurry up and find the treasure.
那我们得要快点找到宝藏才行
Yeah.
是啊
There's only one puzzle left now.
只剩下一个谜题而已
Let's work together, Conan-kun!
一起加油吧 柯南
Ah, I need to go somewhere...
啊 我有个要去的地方…
So you guys go find it yourselves.
你们自己去找吧
Then, let's forget about this odd guy.
那么 就不要管那个不合群的家伙
Let's find the treasure ourselves and split it among ourselves.
就靠我们自己找到宝藏 然后平分吧
Agreed!
赞成
As expected, none of the other bikes have GPS trackers.
果然脚踏车上都没有啊
Director Iwanaga, this is the latest information on the low pressure!
课长 有低气压的最新情报
That's terrible. It's almost like a typhoon.
真伤脑筋 这都可以叫做台风了
Anyway, let's inform the fishing association and hotels.
总之先通知渔协和旅馆吧
Yes, sir.
是
What a pain in the ass...
真伤脑筋啊
Matsumoto and Izuyama didn't return to the hotel.
松本和伊豆山没回饭店
But there's no sign of them leaving the island.
但因为没有离开岛的痕迹
So they must be lurking somewhere.
所以应该是在某处潜伏着
At least one of them was shot with a rifle.
至少有一人遭到来福枪枪击
They would need a doctor, right?
也有治疗的必要吧？
I've checked with the clinics.
我去诊所确认过了
They haven't shown up yet.
不过他们还没现身
About Mabuchi, the owner of the diving shop,
关于潜水店的老板马渊
I've figured out what Conan-kun saw last night.
昨晚柯南看到的是
Matsumoto asked her to prepare a boat for them to escape.
松本拜托她准备逃走用的船只
Let me be clear,
话先说在前面
I have no idea where Matsumoto and the others are hiding.
松本他们躲在哪里我可不知道
It's hard to make money from this diving shop,
光靠潜水店是根本赚不了什么钱
so I agreed to help Matsumoto.
所以我才答应松本
I never thought I'd have such bad luck.
真想不到竟然那么倒楣
I see.
原来如此
The shell casings Takagi-kun took back
高木回收的这些弹壳
were worn-out.
因为非常老旧了
They must have been stored for a very long time.
应该是放了很久的子弹吧？
We're checking with the hunting club about the rifle.
关于来福枪的事情我们正在和猎友会确认
Please come in.
请进
Sorry for the intrusion.
打扰了
I just got a call.
刚刚接到联络
They said that Mineo-san of the hunting club has lost his rifle.
听说猎友会的峰尾先生的猎枪不见了
Is that so?
这样啊
Who's that Mineo-san?
那个峰尾先生是什么人？
He's an old man living all by himself.
他是个独居老人
His niece, Chika Mabuchi, who runs the diving stop, takes care of him.
由经营潜水店的侄女马渊千夏负责照顾他
Go ask Mineo-san for more details!
马上去找峰尾先生询问
And ask Mabuchi-san to come over here as well.
顺便也请马渊小姐来问话
Yes, sir!
我知道了
Please find back the stolen cutlass and pistol for us.
请一定要找回被偷的弯刀和手枪
I'm counting on you!
拜托你们了
We'll do our best.
我们会尽全力的
But we police are all here,
不过 我们警方明明都在这里
why did they wait until now to steal them?
为什么到现在才要去偷呢？
That's right.
是啊
When Uehira-san was the only police officer,
平常只有上平先生一个人
it would be easier to leave this island.
要离开岛也比较简单
Maybe the criminal was worried that if this continued,
恐怕是一直磨蹭下去
it would be only a matter of time before their identities were revealed.
身份的暴露也是迟早的问题吧？
What about the backup from Tokyo?
那个 东京来的支援呢？
Because of the low air pressure,
因为低气压的影响
I heard that the helicopters and ships can't go out.
听说直升机和船都没有办法出航
We have to depend on ourselves.
只能靠我们这些人了
Not only to look for Matsumoto and the others,
无论是找出松本他们
but also to find out the culprit who attempted to kill them.
还是找出危及他们性命的犯人
Here it is.
找到了
Found it!
找到了喔
Great!
太好了
The last hint is really easy.
真是简单呢 最后的提示
"Souls of pirates will go to heaven." The only answer would be the watchtower.
“海盗的灵魂会升天” 所以只有了望台了啊
"The words on the seals are the hint."
“印章的文字是提示”
"Now, let's find out our treasure."
“来吧 找出我们的宝藏吧”
My boss just went to go check on the situation at sea.
老板刚才去看海上的情况
Please wait a moment.
你们先等一下
Okay.
好
Sorry for the wait.
久等了
Sorry.
抱歉
We can't go out to sea today.
看来果然还是无法出海
The waves are really rough.
海浪太大了
Too bad.
真可惜啊
I guess we have no choice.
那也没办法啊
Then, how about we go to a beach?
那我们换个比较平静的海边玩吧
Good morning, Uehira-san.
早安 上平先生
Good morning.
早安
Why do you look so serious?
怎么表情这么沉重？
Did something happen?
发生什么事了吗？
Chika-chan, come with me for a moment.
千夏 跟我来一下
Inspector Megure has something to ask you.
目暮警官有些话想问你
Uncle!
大叔
Yeah, what is it?
嗯 怎么了？
Why did those hunters steal the cutlass and pistol from the Tourism Museum?
那些猎人们为什么从观光馆里偷出弯刀和手枪呢？
Treasure hunters' target should be treasure, right?
宝藏猎人的目的应该是寻宝的不是吗？
But they stole those items.
但是他们却偷走那些东西
That means those items are necessary to find the treasure, right?
也就是说需要寻找到宝藏 那是必要的东西不是吗？
So I think those people have already left for where the treasure is hidden.
所以我想那些人 现在已经出发去了藏宝的地方
Uncle, do you know where it is?
大叔 你知道在哪里吗？
Why are you asking me about this?
为什么要向我打听这种事？
You used to be a treasure hunter too, right?
大叔以前该不会也是宝藏猎人吧？
Even if I were a treasure hunter,
就算我以前是宝藏猎人
how can you be so sure that I know where the treasure is?
也未必就是知道宝藏在哪里的人吧
Didn't you say that yesterday?
昨天大叔不是说过了吗？
Speaking of the treasure hunters, is there really treasure here?
说到宝藏猎人 这里真的有宝藏吗？
Coyotes don't gather where there is no prey,
土狼不会聚集在没有猎物的地方
although it may not be the prey they're expecting.
虽然那未必是它所要的猎物
"Although it may not be the prey they're expecting."
“虽然那未必是它所要的猎物”
In other words,
也就是说
you know what the treasure is, right?
你应该知道宝藏是什么吧？
Follow me.
跟我来
Why are some of the numbers read, and some blue?
为什么数字分成红色和蓝色呢？
Give me the scissors.
拿剪刀来
Ah, okay.
啊 好
There are two questions.
问题有两个呢
Besides the question that why the numbers are separated into two colors,
除了数字分成红蓝两种之外
there is another question, what do these numbers mean?
还有数字本身代表的意思
Could the numbers be the address of the island?
数字会不会是这座岛的地址呢？
Oh right, let's go ask Uncle!
对了 我们去问大叔吧？
Uncle!
大叔
But then again, what would Inspector Megure want to ask Mabuchi-san?
话说回来 目暮警官要和马渊说什么话呢？
Could it be related to the case?
会不会是跟案件有关吧？
There must be a mistake.
一定是哪里搞错了吧
You guys get in the car.
你们先上车吧
Okay!
好
How about you put this in the car for me too?
帮我也把这个一起放上车如何
Wait, you...
等一下 我说你…
Get back in the car!
你给我上车
You don't want anything to happen to your friend, do you?
你不想看到你朋友受伤吧？
Uncle, did you used to be a treasure hunter?
大叔以前是宝藏猎人吗？
Yeah, when I was young,
是啊 在年轻的时候
I came to this island to find Anne and Mary's treasure.
为了寻找安和玛莉的宝藏来到这个岛上
And I've been here ever since.
然后就一直在这里了
I fell in love with a woman on the island, married and started a family with her.
爱上岛上的女人并结婚成家
Then I became a fisherman.
当起了渔夫
This map is 300-year-old.
这是300年前的东西了
You were right.
你想的没错
They are drawn according to this map.
这是照着这张地图画出来的
These numbers are drawn by Iwanaga,
这是观光课长岩永照着跟这张一样的旧地图画出来的
Because, so far, no one has been able to solve these codes.
因为是还没有人解开的暗号
This map may have been drawn 300 years ago.
这张地图可能是300年前画出来的
And, by Anne Bonny herself.
而且还是安·宝妮画的
Yeah...
嗯…
If so, could it be that...
这么说来 难道…
we'll find the real treasure if we solve these codes?
如果能解开暗号的话 就能发现真正的宝藏？
That's right.
没错
There were no addresses here 300 years ago, I guess.
如果是300年前的话应该还没有地址吧
The most common way to solve this would be to use the alphabet.
最常用的解法应该是英文字母
So, 5 is...
这么说5就是…
5 is... A, B, C, D, E... It's E!
5的话 ABCDE 是E！
Right.
没错
7 is G.
7是G
12 is... A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, K, L...
12是…ABCDEFGHIJKL…
The 12th one is L!
第12个是L喔
L!
L！
Letters are all written down.
这样全部就写好了
The red numbers are on top,
上面的是红色数字
and the blue numbers are on the bottom.
下面的是蓝色数字
All the numbers have been converted to letters.
全部都已经由数字换成英文字母
Now we just have to arrange them.
接下来就是怎么排列了
Is it someone's name?
是不是人名呢？
Red could be the last name, and blue could be the first name or something.
红色的是姓 蓝色的是名字之类的
Good point.
这想法不错喔
Could this be a name related to pirates?
这会不会是跟海盗有关系的名字呢？
Well... it's possible.
嗯…大概是吧
Look, look!
你看你看
If we arrange them like this, it looks like a name of a person.
这么排的话 就很像人名了
"Jolly"...
“JOLLY”啊…
Jolly...
JOLLY…
You two, run!
你们两个快逃
Don't move!
不要动
Ran!
小兰
Seems like you know a little karate, little girl.
你似乎会一点点空手道啊 小姑娘
If you do anything stupid, I'll kill your friend immediately.
不老实一点 你朋友的小命可就不保啰
This is our boat...
我们店里的船…
Why would it be in this place...
为什么会在这种地方…
I asked your boss to prepare it.
这是我拜托你老板准备的
I paid her.
还付钱给她
How could...
怎么会…
You're of no use anymore.
你已经没用处了
Because we don't have enough oxygen tanks.
因为氧气筒不够
Kimiko-san!
喜美子
Don't move!
不要动
You! Don't move!
你不要给我乱动
Hurry up and get on the board!
快点给我上船
I'm really not good at this kind of thing.
我对这种最不在行了
What about this?
那么 这样的话呢？
What is this?
这是什么啊？
Could it be Grroe?
嗯…会不会是GRROE呢？
Jolly Grroe?
JOLLY GRROE？
No.
不对
Roger.
ROGER
Jolly Roger.
JOLLY ROGER
Jolly Roger?
JOLLY ROGER？
Who's that?
那是谁啊？
Some famous pirate?
是有名的海盗吗？
The direct translation would be "Happy Roger", huh?
直译的话 就是“愉快的ROGER”
Jolly Roger...
JOLLY ROGER呢
was the last thing sailors wanted to see in the 17th century.
是西元1700年代 航海员最不想看到的东西
It is said, originally, this name
据说这个名字的由来
consists of "Jolly Rouge", which means "Red Flag",
是由意思为“红色旗子”的JOLLY ROUGE
and "Old Roger", which means "Devil".
跟意思为“恶魔”的OLD ROGER所组成的
Flag?
旗子？
Devil?
恶魔？
That's right.
没错
The so-called "Jolly Roger"
所谓的JOLLY ROGER
is this pirate flag drawn on this map.
就是画在这张地图上的海盗旗
Conan-kun, you're awesome!
柯南好厉害喔
Correct answer.
标准答案
What is this?
这个是？
About 300 years ago,
这张是大约300年前
it was drawn by a Spanish sailor who was passing through the sea off this island.
一个经过这座岛外海的西班牙船员所画的
Since then, the island has sunk into the sea.
从那之后这座岛就沉没到海底去
I heard that it was because of methane gas or something.
听说是因为甲烷之类的沼气的关系
It is said that the part of Yorioya Island that used to be exposed above water was larger before.
听说赖亲岛以前露出海面的部份比现在还大
About 300 years ago, earthquakes caused it to sink into the ocean depths.
在大约300年前因为地震沉入海底
That's why it looks like this now.
才会变成我们现在所看到的样子
Yorioya Island...
赖亲岛…
Is there a treasure hidden on that island?
有宝藏藏在那座岛？
Yes, it's possible.
嗯 很有可能
But there should be other clues.
可是 应该还有其他线索
Clues that suggest the exact location.
应该还有暗示确切位置的线索才对
What's wrong, Conan?
怎么了 柯南？
Did you think of something?
你想到什么了吗？
The pirate flag on this ancient map.
这张旧地图上面的海盗旗
The skull's teeth...
那个骷髅头的牙齿
Don't you think they look like characters?
是不是很像文字？
Really.
真的耶
They look like letters from the alphabet.
看起来像英文字母呢
The teeth on top are DOS,
上面的牙齿是 DOS
The teeth on the bottom are DIOSAS.
下面的牙齿是 DIOSAS
What does it mean?
是什么意思呢？
Dos Diosas.
DOS DIOSAS
In Spanish, it means "two goddesses".
在西班牙语的意思就是“两个女神”
Awesome!
好厉害
Not bad for you, Haibara-san!
真不愧是灰原
Is that all?
就只有这些了吗…
We must go to the island to check out the rest.
剩下的就只能到那座岛上去看看才行…
But aren't the treasure hunters looking for treasure in the sea?
可是 那些宝藏猎人不是在海里找宝藏吗？
So, the treasure is hidden on the seabed?
那么 宝藏是藏在海底啰？
No, if it was on the seabed,
不对 如果是这样的话
there would have been a hint about the sea.
应该会找到有关海的提示才对
And Poseidon is the male god of the sea.
而且海神波塞顿又是男神
Those guys are probably looking for other entrance.
那些家伙大概是在找其他入口
The entrance of the two goddesses
两个女神的入口
collapsed during the last earthquake.
在之前的地震就已经坍塌了
Adults are unable to pass through.
如果是大人的话应该是进不去才对
So they have found the entrance.
原来他们已经找到入口了
That's why even with the police investigating on the island,
所以警方都已经进驻岛上着手调查了
they still decided to risk stealing the cutlass and the pistol.
还不惜冒着危险 偷走那把弯刀跟手枪
The girl from the diving shop!
是那个潜水的大姐姐
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Where's Mouri-san?
毛利先生呢？
He's not here. He should be at the district office.
他不在这里 他应该在区公所才对
Ran-chan and Sonoko-chan were kidnapped...
小兰跟园子被抓走了…
They were taken to the boat...
她们被带上船…
Who was it? Who took them away?
是谁？是谁把她们抓走的？
Matsumoto... That treasure hunter.
松本…那个宝藏猎人
They must have gone to Yorioya Island!
他们一定是去赖亲岛了
You guys, go to the district office and tell Uncle Mouri about this.
你们几个 赶快到区公所告诉叔叔这件事
Got it!
我知道了
Be careful.
你要小心
Mhm.
嗯
Uncle.
大叔
Could you please drive the boat?
可以请你开船吗？
I need you to take me to that island.
我想请你把我送到那座岛上去
What?
什么？
It's not because of the treasure.
我不是为了宝藏
I want to save Ran-nee-chan and Sonoko-chan.
而是为了去救小兰姐姐他们
Shinichi.
新一
Conan-kun, I heard that Ran-kun and Sonoko were kidnapped, right?
柯南 听说小兰他们被抓走了是吗？
Mhm.
嗯
I know you'll go save her, even if I tell you not to go.
反正我怎么阻止你 你也是非去不可吧
Wait a minute, I have something for you.
等一下 我有东西要给你
I'm going to get the boat ready.
我先去准备船
Got it.
我知道了
Take these with you.
你把这些带着
These are mini-oxygen tanks.
这是小型的氧气筒
Just pull this from here,
从这里拉开
put it in your mouth, and you'll get 10 minutes worth of oxygen.
用嘴咬住就可以吸大约10分钟的氧气
But unfortunately, I only have two of them.
不过可惜的是 我只有2支
So, use them as a last resort.
这些要到最后关头才用
Thank you, Professor.
谢谢你 博士
You two share one oxygen tank.
你们两个就共用一桶氧气筒
Now that you're already here, you don't need us anymore, do you?
你们既然已经来到这里 就应该不需要我们了吧
You gotta stay with us a little longer.
你们还得要陪我们一下子才行
Hurry up and get everything ready!
快点准备下水
Could it be...
难道说…
Sonoko!
园子
It's your turn, little girl.
该你上场了 小姑娘
What exactly do you want us to do?
你到底想要我们做什么？
Your turn's next.
晚一点会轮到你
What?
什么？
Ran and Sonoko were kidnapped by Matsumoto?
小兰他们被松本给抓走了？
Where did they go?
他们到哪里去了？
They went to an island!
就是到岛上去了啊
They went to Yorioya Island!
他们去赖亲岛了
They've known where the treasure is. They're going to get it now!
他们知道了宝藏在哪里 就去拿宝藏了
Please get the boat ready as soon as possible.
请你马上准备船
We're going to save Ran and Sonoko.
我们要去救小兰他们
Got it.
我知道了
But why did those guys take hostages with them?
可是 那些家伙为什么要抓人质
If they are going to find the treasure,
如果是要去找宝藏
it's troublesome to take hostages, isn't it?
有人质反而会不方便吧
Because they have some other use.
因为他们有其他用处
Some other use?
其他用处？
They were injured by rifle shots last night.
他们昨天晚上被来福枪射伤了
The place they're going to dive down
他们接下来要潜下去的地方
is the same place they were attacked by sharks yesterday.
就是昨天被鲨鱼袭击的地方
Are they going to be used as bait?
是要拿他们当诱饵吗？
Most likely.
很有可能
Right there!
就在那里
As expected...
果然…
What should we do? There is not much time left.
怎么办？ 已经没什么时间了
I'm going to Yorioya Island.
我要去赖亲岛
What?
什么？
I'm small enough to pass through the entrance of the two goddesses, right?
如果是我的话 应该可以进去女神的入口吧？
Not much oxygen left.
氧气快没了
Impressive, you're still alive.
真是厉害 你们竟然还活着
Go get those torches and come over here.
去拿那边的火把过来这里
Otherwise, you won't be able to see the way
不然根本看不到路吧
You'll only die if you stay here.
反正继续待在那里也是死路一条
Keep moving.
快点走
Don't push me!
不要推啦
This place is...
这里是…？
We've been here several times.
我们已经来过这里好几次
I must get the treasure of Anne Bonny and Mary Read today!
今天我一定要把安·宝妮跟玛莉·丽德的宝藏拿到手
Stay there for now, you two.
你们暂时先乖乖地待在那里
A little further ahead of you is a small temple.
再往上走一点就会看见一个小祠堂
There are statues of two goddesses inside.
里面供奉着两个女神的神像
The entrance is right behind there.
入口就在那后面
Got it!
我知道了
You can only stay for 30 minutes at most.
最多只能待30分钟
Otherwise, you won't be able to come back.
不然会回不来的
Thank you!
嗯 谢谢你
I'll definitely bring Ran-nee-chan and Sonoko-nee-chan back!
我一定会把小兰姐姐跟园子姐姐给带回来的
Anne Bonny and Mary Read...
安·宝妮跟玛莉·丽德啊…
Strange, an adult should be able to go through too.
奇怪了 大人应该也可以过去的啊
Last week, an earthquake caused a landslide which blocked the road.
上星期因为地震造成土石崩落 把道路给堵住了
I see. The earthquake made this entrance bigger.
原来如此 是因为地震洞口才又变大的
Could it be that Ran have already been...
难不成小兰他们被…
No, since they brought them here,
不对 既然都已经把他们带到这里
I don't think they would kill them.
应该不会将他们灭口
But...
但是…
Last night Matsumoto and his teammate were injured by rifle shots.
昨天晚上松本他们被来福枪射伤了
As soon as they dive down,
只要一潜水
the smell of blood would attract sharks.
血的味道就会吸引鲨鱼过来
So?
所以呢？
Ran-san and Sonoko must have been used as bait.
小兰他们应该是被抓来当诱饵的
Wait a minute, Mouri-san!
请等一下 毛利先生
What are you doing?
你在干什么啊？
Let go of me! I can't just leave them alone!
放开我 我怎么可能放着他们不管
It's no use, Mouri-san.
没用的 毛利先生
The weather is going to get worse.
接下来天气会越变越糟的啊
I don't care! Let go of me!
我不管 放开我
I'm sorry.
不好意思
What should we do now?
接下来该怎么办？
We have to go back for now.
也只能回去了
Although it's hard to make this decision...
虽然很遗憾…
Hurry and come inside.
快进来里面吧
It's too dangerous to stay out here.
待在外面太危险了
But...
但是
Conan-kun, Ran-onee-san and Sonoko-onee-san are in danger now.
柯南、小兰姐姐跟园子姐姐他们的处境更危险
Yeah...
嗯…
Indeed...
就是说啊…
The water level has begun to go down.
水开始退了
The tide is ebbing, right?
现在是退潮吧
Are we going into that cave?
难道要进去那个洞？
You're right.
你说得没错
That cave is a shortcut to the treasure.
那个洞口是通往宝藏的捷径
Okay, bring those oxygen tanks and follow us.
好 带着那些氧气筒跟上来
So the legend of the pirates is true.
原来海盗的传说是真的
It seems so.
好像是这样
Put the oxygen tanks down. You two, go in first.
把氧气筒放下 你们先进去
Ah, but...
啊 可是…
Shut up! Just go inside!
闭嘴 快进去
Skeletons... Skeletons... Skeletons...
骷髅…骷髅…骷髅
Looks like this place is safe this time.
这次看起来没问题呢
The gas...
是沼气
Gas?
沼气？
When the wind isn't blowing hard enough, this place is full of gas.
风比较小的时候 这里会充满沼气
That's why you asked us to go first?
所以才叫我们先走…
What else do you think we took you here?
不然你以为让你们跟着我们是要干嘛
Hurry up and keep moving.
快点走
What's that?
那是什么？
This is it!
就是这个
I found it!
我找到了
What an idiot.
真是个笨蛋
Who asked you to put this fake one in? That's why you died.
就是因为用这种假东西镶进去才会没命的
You must use this one...
用这个就可以…
You, go open it.
你去打开
Me?
我？
I'll do it.
我来开
Ran!
小兰
Bah! We failed again?
呿 还是不行吗？
Just give up!
还是放弃吧
So that's it. I see.
原来如此 是这样啊
Did you figure out?
你知道了吗？
Anne and Mary always fought back to back.
安跟玛莉他们是背靠对着背在战斗的
That means...
也就是说
they should be put this way.
就是这样
We found it! We found it!
找到了 找到了
Give me the torch.
把火给我
Impressive.
太壮观了
Treasure... Where's the treasure?
宝藏呢 宝藏在哪里？
No rush!
不要着急嘛
Ran, what should we do now?
小兰 现在怎么办？
Now we have a chance to run away,
虽然可以趁机逃走
but without oxygen tanks,
但是没有氧气筒
it's impossible to get to the surface in this kind of terrible weather.
也不可能在这种恶劣的天气里浮到海面上去
That's right...
也对…
We can only wait here for help.
我们只能在这里等待救援了
That's right.
没错
There's wind.
有风
There's a channel down there.
下面有通道
Damn it!
可恶
There's no treasure anywhere!
到处都没有宝藏
There's not even a dime! Not to mention the treasure!
什么宝藏 连个一毛钱都没有啊
I don't know who it is,
虽然不知道是谁
there must be someone who came first and took it all!
一定是被先来的人给全部拿走了
Hey, this isn't like what you told me before!
喂 这跟之前说的不一样啊
I came to this place because you said there was treasure!
因为你说有宝藏 我才来这种地方的
Shut up! You're annoying!
吵死了 闭嘴
Anyway, there's no other choice. We gotta get out of here right now.
没办法 这样的话我们只好先开溜了
But first, let's get rid of the deadweight.
先把没用处的东西解决掉
I'm sorry.
不好意思
But this is your destiny.
这就是你们的宿命
Don't move!
不要动
Ran, I'll trust you to watch my back.
小兰 我的背后就交给你了喔
Sonoko, be careful!
园子你也要小心
Damn it!
可恶
This woman is a fighter!
这个女人太厉害了
And she's a good one.
她的确很厉害
But no matter how good they are,
不过 不管她们有多厉害
they're no match for this.
都比不上这个
Always play your trump card last.
王牌总是最后才亮出来的
Get down, you two!
你们两个快趴下
Are you all right?
你们没事吧？
Ran-nee-chan! Sonoko-nee-chan!
小兰姐姐 园子姐姐
Well done, little man!
干得好啊 年轻人
How did you know about this place?
你怎么会知道这个地方的？
There is a tunnel between this place and Yorioya Island.
这里跟赖亲岛是相通的
So the pirates' treasure really exists.
果然海盗的宝藏是真的
There is no treasure here.
没有什么宝藏啊
They said that it was all taken by someone who came to this place first.
他们说被先来的人给全部拿走了
So that is the end!
就是这样啰
What a pity, huh?
真是可惜啊
I guess it's okay to show your face now.
你现在出来也没关系了吧？
You were sneaking behind me and following me here, weren't you?
你是跟在我后面偷偷进来的吧？
Inspector, we can take the boat out now.
警官 现在可以搭船出海的吧
The wind has died down now.
现在风势已经变小了
Mouri-san.
毛利先生
The weather forecast said the storm won't stop until dawn.
天气预报说要到天亮 暴风雨才会停止
But... You can look for yourself.
但是 你仔细看看嘛
It's really dying down.
真的已经变小了
Please calm down, Mouri-san.
你先冷静下来 毛利先生
How can I calm down after this happened?
发生这种事 我怎么可能冷静下来啊
Ran was kidnapped!
小兰可是被抓走了啊
But the only one who went save her was that brat with glasses!
可是去救她的人 只有那个戴眼镜的小鬼而已
We adults can do nothing but wait!
我们这些大人就只能咬着手指干等
Mouri-kun!
毛利
I understand how you feel,
你的心情我很了解
but if we can't go out to sea by boat,
但是如果不能搭船出海
there is nothing we can do about it.
我们也无能为力啊
As soon as the storm subsides, we will go save Ran-kun and Sonoko immediately.
只要风雨一变小 我们一定马上出海去救小兰他们
Please try to be patient now.
你就先忍耐一下吧
Damn it!
可恶
I guess it's okay to show your face now.
你现在出来也没关系了吧
You were sneaking behind me and following me here, weren't you?
你是跟在我后面偷偷进来的吧
Iwanaga-san.
岩永先生
Don't say like that. "Sneaking" is kind of an ugly word.
真是的 说什么偷偷地也太难听了
I was just trying to save them.
我只是想救她们两个而已
Then why are you carrying a rifle here?
那你为什么还带着来福枪
Because I heard they were international fugitives.
因为听说他们是国际通缉犯
That rifle is the one stolen from Mineo-san, right?
那把来福枪是峰尾先生被偷的枪吧？
No...
不…不是
You brought it to stop them from taking the treasure away, right?
是为了宝藏不被抢走才带来吧？
It has nothing to do with the treasure!
这跟宝藏完全没关系
Iwanaga-san.
岩永先生
You said the codes for the treasure hunt you gave us
你说过你给我们玩的寻宝游戏的暗号
were all your ideas?
是你自己想出来的吧？
Ah...Yeah.
啊…是啊
But I saw the same codes at Mima-san's house.
但是 我在美马先生家里看到相同的数字暗号喔
They were from a 300-year-old map left behind by Anne Bonny.
就是传说安·宝妮所留下来的300年前的地图
That means...
这就表示
you has seen that map before, Iwanaga-san.
岩永先生之前看过那张地图啰？
In other words,
也就是说
you couldn't solve the mystery of the treasure map on your own,
你想把自己解不开的宝藏地图之谜
so you wanted the tourists on the island to solve it for you, right?
让岛上的观光客帮你解开对吧？
Come to think of it,
这么说来
you even tried to persuade my dad to join the treasure hunt too.
你那时候也极力劝爸爸参加寻宝
I see.
原来如此
Compared to these kids,
与其交给这些小孩子
the probability of a famous detective solving it would be much higher.
让名侦探去解谜 解开的可能性还比较大
Besides, in order to track the participants' movements,
而且 为了确认参加者的行踪
you also installed GPS trackers on the rental bikes, right?
你还在出租的脚踏车上装了全球定位系统吧？
That was because I must protect the safety of the participants.
那是为了保护参加者的安全
If you changed the numbers on the map into the letters of the alphabet, it would be "Jolly Roger".
把地图上的数字转成英文字母的话就是“JOLLY ROGER”
That is, "pirate flag".
也就是“海盗旗”
This Yorioya Island used to look like a skull.
这座赖亲岛以前看起来就像骷髅头
That's why Anne Bonny left these clues.
安·宝妮才留下这些线索
I think the origin of the name "Yorioya"
我想赖亲岛的“赖亲”这个名字的由来
came from the pronunciation of the words "Jolly Roger".
是从JOLLY ROGER的发音转变来的吧
I'm sure you've thought of that too, Iwanaga-san.
我想岩永先生你应该也有想到这点
But there's another meaning behind the "Jolly Roger".
但是JOLLY ROGER还有另一个意思
What?
什么？
On the real map, there is a pirate flag, or Jolly Roger, right?
真正的地图上画了海盗旗 JOLLY ROGER对吧？
There is a second hint on the skull.
在那个骷髅头上画着第二个提示
Dos Diosas, two goddesses.
DOS DIOSAS 两个女神
Conan-kun...
柯南…
That's right.
没错
You should have seen them when you followed me.
你在尾随我到这里的时候应该有看到
The statues of the two goddesses in that small temple.
供奉着两尊女神像的小祠堂
They suggested that there was an entrance.
那就是暗示着那里是入口
So that's it.
原来如此
How did you know that?
为什么你会知道这种事？
Damn it, was I wrong from the beginning?
可恶 我一开始就猜错了吗…？
You tampered with the buoyancy control jacket,
在浮力衣上动手脚
and shot the treasure hunters with the rifle.
用来福枪袭击那些宝藏猎人
You did all of those, didn't you, Iwanaga-san?
都是岩永先生你做的吧？
Both behind the cave,
在洞穴后面
and at the place where the bullet shells from the rifle were dropped,
还有掉了来福枪弹壳的地方
there were tire marks of your bicycle left.
都有你脚踏车轮胎的痕迹
I made some mistakes that even a schoolboy would notice.
我的确是犯了一些连小学生都知道的失误
It wasn't a schoolboy.
可不是小学生喔
It was Uncle Kogoro.
是小五郎叔叔啦
I heard these all from Uncle Kogoro.
刚刚都是从小五郎叔叔那里听来的
He told me that...
叔叔他说过
Iwanaga-san had the smell of gunpowder on him.
岩永先生他身上有火药味
It's probably because that rifle was too old.
可能是因来福枪太老旧
So when he fired it, the gunpowder residues would fly all over the place.
开枪的时候 火药的残渣会大量飞出
What?
什么嘛
I knew it.
我就知道
As expected of the famous detective, Kogoro Mouri.
真不愧是名侦探毛利小五郎
Earthquake?
地震？
It stopped.
停住了
Not good. We gotta get out of here!
不好了 我们得快点逃走
That's right. We should take those two treasure hunters with us.
说的也是 带那两个宝藏猎人一起走
Mhm.
嗯
Iwanaga-san, please give me a hand!
岩永先生也来帮忙
That's bad!
糟了
What should we do? The entrance is blocked.
怎么办 入口被堵住了
It's gas.
是沼气
Let's get to the ship!
总之先到船上
Hurry up!
快点
Damn it, if this continues...
可恶 再这么下去的话…
Conan-kun, what should we do now?
柯南 接下来该怎么办？
Anyway, let's bring them to the cabin.
总之 先把他们放到船舱去
Just in case, hook an oxygen tank up to them.
以防万一先让他们吸氧气筒的氧气
Don't let them breathe in the gas.
不要让他们吸入沼气
And Ran-nee-chan, you two can use these.
还有 小兰姐姐你们就用这个
What are these?
这是什么？
They're mini-oxygen tanks invented by Professor Agasa.
这是阿笠博士发明的小型氧气筒
Conan-kun, where is yours?
柯南你的呢？
I have another one, it's okay.
我还有 没问题
I see...
这样啊…
Damn, what should I do?
可恶 该怎么办
If this goes on, the gas will...
这样下去的话 沼气就…
Gas?
沼气？
The gas is probably methane.
这些沼气大概是甲烷
It would be concentrated near the top of the cave.
应该集中在洞顶附近
If we can make use of the gas...
如果利用沼气的话
Is there anything... Anything I can use?
有什么…有什么可以用的？
Found it.
找到了
Ran-nee-chan. Sonoko-nee-chan.
小兰姐姐 园子姐姐
Listen to me carefully.
你们仔细地听我说
Since the water can flow into this place,
海水能流进这里
the rock layer is probably not very thick.
就表示岩层应该不是很厚
So, I want to detonate the gas and blow up the top of the cave.
所以我想引爆沼气 炸开洞顶
This way, we can let the whole ship...
就能让整艘船…
Are you gonna let us to ride the ship out to escape?
难…难道要搭这艘船逃离这里？
Is that okay?
没问题吗？
I don't know.
我不知道
But at this rate,
可是 这样下去的话
we'll all die from methane poisoning,
大家会因为吸入过量沼气中毒身亡
or we'll drown in the sea.
或是等着被海水灭顶
Since we'll die anyway, why don't we...
既然都是死路一条 不如…
We might as well give it a try.
也只能孤注一掷了…
Mhm.
嗯！
What are we going to do, Conan-kun?
我们要怎么做呢 柯南？
I'll kick the chain upwards,
等一下我会把那边的铁链往上踢
letting it hit the rocks at the top of the cave.
让它打到洞顶的岩石
If it goes well, it will create a spark, which should be able to make the gas explode.
顺利的话 应该就能擦出火花然后引爆沼气
Ran-nee-chan, you two go into the cabin and breathe through the oxygen tanks.
小兰姐姐你们就先进去船舱 用氧气筒呼吸
When the gas explodes, all of the oxygen in the air will be consumed in an instant.
我想爆炸时周围的氧气会在瞬间消耗完
Conan-kun, what about you?
柯南你呢？
I'll be fine. After kicking the chain up, I'll run into the cabin.
没问题 我把铁链踢上去之后 就会马上跑进船舱的
No need to worry about me.
你放心吧
I got it.
我知道了
Inspector...
警官…
Mhm...
嗯…
Get the boat ready!
快去准备船
Prepare for the rescue operation!
准备出发救人
Yes, sir!
是
Everything is ready here, Conan-kun.
这里已经准备好了 柯南
Alright.
好
Not good...
糟了…
Conan-kun. Conan-kun!
柯南 柯南
Conan-kun, hang in there!
柯南你振作一点
Ran...
小兰…
Hurry up! Hurry up!
快一点 快一点
Full speed!
速度再加快
Pirate ship?
海盗船？
Ran!
小兰
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
I'm fine!
我没事
Finally, we're saved!
总算得救了
Everybody, run!
大家快逃
Watch out!
危险
Jump into the sea!
快跳进海里
Sonoko!
园子
Quick!
动作快
So, did you find the treasure?
那么 结果有找到宝藏吗？
No.
没有
All we found was that dilapidated pirate ship.
找到的只有一艘破旧的海盗船
Maybe that ship is the treasure.
那艘船就是宝藏吧？
Maybe the map left behind by Anne Bonny wasn't a treasure map.
说不定 安·宝妮所留下来的地图并不是藏宝图
It was a message for Mary Read, who was in prison back then.
而是为了留给在监狱的玛莉·丽德的讯息
A message?
讯息？
I'm here! I will always be here waiting for you!
我在这里喔　我一直都在这里等你喔
Shinichi.
新一
Just kidding.
开玩笑的
Sonoko!
园子
How can you be so sure about that, you little brat?
你这小鬼说的跟真的似的
No... Maybe what he said was true.
不…说不定他说得没错
Maybe Anne built that ship
说不定那艘船
for Mary, in preparation for the day
是她为了跟日后逃狱的玛莉
when Mary escaped from the prison and conquer the seven seas with her again.
两人携手再度征服七大洋
That's why she built that ship.
才建造那艘船的
But... She never thought Mary would fall ill in prison,
可是 没想到玛莉在狱中病倒
and died that way.
就这么死去
Anne waited for her until the day she died.
安就这样等着玛莉直到老死
And then, the ship was left behind in that coffin-like cave under the sea,
然后 遗留下来的那艘船则是在形如海底棺木的洞穴里
waiting for the day when it would sail to the sea again.
一直等待再度扬帆航向大海的那一天
And today, three hundred years later,
而且 三百年后的今天
it made its first and last voyage,
它的第一次也是最后一次的出航
carrying all of you to the surface.
就是载着你们送出海面
After that, it vanished into the sea, following in its master's footsteps.
之后就追随着他们的主人般地消失在海面上了
I guess I said something I shouldn't have.
我说了一些很不适合自己的话啊
So, just forget it.
你们就忘记吧
Since it happened 300 years ago, nobody will know the truth.
既然是300年前的 是真是假都还是个谜啊
No, it's true that Anne had been waiting for Mary.
不 安一直等待着玛莉是真的
Uncle Mouri.
叔叔
The proof is below the skull of the pirate flag.
证据就在海盗旗骷髅下面
There are Anne and Mary's pistol and cutlass on it.
画着安与玛莉的手枪与弯刀
Well...
那个…
Ran-nee-chan, well...
小兰姐姐 那个…
Why did you know I didn't have an oxygen tank back there?
为什么那时候你会知道我没有氧气筒呢？
Because you're a lot like... that guy.
因为你跟那个家伙很像
I remember when we were in eighth grade,
我记得是国二的时候吧
there was a sudden rainstorm on our way home from school.
放学回家的路上突然下起大雨
Geez!
真是的
Here, take it.
来 拿去用吧
You need to hurry back home, right?
你不是要快点回家吗？
Yeah, thanks.
嗯 谢谢
What about you, Shinichi?
那新一你呢？
I'm a detective, you idiot!
笨蛋 我可是个侦探耶
I knew this would happen.
我早就想到会有这种状况
So I brought an extra umbrella.
所以我多带了一把伞
You did?
真的吗？
That's great! I have a date with my mom.
太好了 我跟妈妈有约
I'll borrow this, then.
那我就先借走啰
I'll give it back to you tomorrow!
我明天会还你
Okay.
好
But Shinichi didn't bring an extra umbrella.
可是新一根本就没有带伞
He walked home soaking wet, and ended up getting a cold.
结果全身湿透回家 还感冒了
Right. That's why I said you're just like him at that time.
没错 所以我才说那时候你跟他很像
You looked just like that stubborn big idiot.
跟那个老爱逞强 大笨蛋的脸很像
Well, so sorry for being such an idiot.
真不好意思 我是笨蛋